ERIC UTRERA SUST

Sofia, Bulgaria • +359882346680 • ebutrera910322@gmail.com © ebutrera9103.github.io/



Computer Science Engineer

Summary

Software Engineer with 6+ years of experience in the IT field. I have been mostly concentrating on front-end and back-end development, gained significant experience with technologies such as JavaScript, React, Nextjs, Angular, TypeScript, CSS, Microservices, JSON, SQL, as well as NodeJS, Symfony Framework, Bash etc. In terms of DB management, I have experience with MongoDB, MySQL and PostgreSQL. In most of my projects, I have taken part in all stages of the development lifecycle, gaining knowledge in software architecture, testing and deployment, code reviewing, as well as team and project leadership. In addition, I have hands-on working experience on Al-based projects. I handles tasks such as designing the architecture of the whole system, developing back-end code in Node.js and the front-end of the application according to the best practices for React, testing new features, deploying new releases, tracking issues in GitHub, performing code reviews, maintaining web interface installed on Linux CentOS as well as leading the team, driving workflow, and preparing and presenting demo presentations

Work experience

2021 - Actually Software Developer

Deutsche Telekom (https://www.telekom.de/start)

Icarus IoT (Node, TypeGraphQL, MongoDB, Microservices, Kafka)

2022 - March 2022 Software Developer Freelancer

Siili Solutions (https://www.siili.com/)

Ruukki project (ReactJs, Sass, Flexbox, Grid)

2019 - 2020 Software Developer

Tropix Media & Entertainment (http://tropixme.com/)

-Developer **Tropix WebSite** (Angular, Sass, Bootstrap, Microservices)

-Developer **Cubannes** (Angular, Sass, Bootstrap, Microservices)

-Developer MAM+ (React, Sass, Bootstrap, Microservices)

-Developer Talent: (React, Sass, Bootstrap, Node)

-Artificial Intelligence Services: (Python, TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV)

Tropix Media & Entertainment (http://tropixme.com/)

2017 - 2019 Project Manager and Software Developer Freelancer

Tresite Company (https://www.tresite.com/)

-Developer and Project Manager: **Weekdone Platform** (Symfony, Bootstrap, Sass, MySQL, Monolithic Architecture)

-Developer and Project Manager: **Whatsapp Agents** (Symfony, Reactjs, Bootstrap, Sass, Microservices)

-Developer and Project Manager: **Support Service Platform through WhatsApp** (Express, Nodejs,Reactjs, Sass, Bootstrap, Sass, Microservices)

-Developer and Project Manager: **News subscription platform in Whatsapp** (Symfony, React, Microservices)

-Developer and Project Manager: **Inventory System**(Express, Nodejs,Reactjs, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Cypress, Mocha, Chai, Microservices)

-Developer and Project Manager: **Gym Plataform** (Express, Nodejs, Reactjs, GraphQL, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Cypress, Mocha, Chai, Microservices)

-Developer and Project Manager: **Whatsapp Food** (Express, Nodejs, Reactjs, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Cypress, Mocha, Chai, Microservices)

-Developer and Project Manager: **Whatsapp Evolution** (Express, Nodejs, Reactjs, Socket.io, MongoDB, RabbitMQ, Cypress, Mocha, Chai, Microservices)

	-Developer and Project Manag RabbitMQ, Cypress, Mocha, Ch	er : Whatsapp Informative (Express, Nodejs Reactjs, Socket.io, MongoDB, nai, Microservices)			
2014 - 2017	Project Manager and Software Developer				
	University Informatics Sciences -Developer and Project Manager Redcuba Search Engines (Angular, RESTfull APIs, Symfony, Apache Nutch, Apache Solr, InfluxDB, Grafana, ELK) -Expert SOLID Principle and Design Patterns -Artificial Intelligence jobs achieving publications: https://csce.ucmss.com/cr/books/2018/LFS/CSREA2018/ICA9015.pdf,				
				http://journal.sepln.org/sepln/ojs/ojs/index.php/pln/article/view/5641	
					Education
			2010 - 2015	Computer Science Engineer	
	University of Informatics Sciences				
		Skills ———————————————————————————————————			
Databases		Operative Systems			
MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Neo4j, DynamoDB		Linux(Centos, Ubuntu, Linux Mint), Windows			
Programing languages		Tools			
PHP, Css, JavaScript, TypeScript, SQL, Python, Bash		React, Express, Nodejs, Nextjs, Angular, Symfony, JSON, Git, Apache Solr, Postman, Gulp, Redux, Apache Nutch, Grafana, InfluxDB, ELK, Suricata, AWS			
		Languages			
-English(English leve l	B2 in the Common European Framewo				
-Spanish(Native)	·				
. , ,					

Created with **TVisualCV**